### Contact

patricialt@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/patriciatenace-a1a764a (LinkedIn) www.aacn.org/ (Company) nursingworld.org/ (Company) www.ena.org (Company)

### Top Skills

Nursing Hospitals Healthcare

#### Certifications

ACLS Instructor BLS Instructor

Honors-Awards

Phi Theta Kappa

# Patricia Tenace

Travel Nurse at Nightingale Nurses

Augusta, Georgia Area

## Summary

I enjoy the opportunity to learn and teach evidence based practices in the care of my patients. I have learned about various roles including the role of the Registered Nurse within the healthcare team. How important each member of the team is and how important my role is as a clinical practice leader. I also have had the opportunity to sit in on a unit council. Through new experiences with patient care I have built a reputation as an outstanding team member and someone that other nurses look up to. I pride myself in learning new techniques to care for my patients in the most cost effective ways, and to plan care for patients with diverse clinical issues.

## Experience

Nightingale Nurses
Travel Nurse
April 2020 - Present (3 months)
South Bend-Mishawaka Region

Travel nurse for Tele, PCU and ICU.

Doctors Hospital of Augusta, LLC 2 years 6 months

Registered Nurse, Progressive Care Unit August 2018 - April 2020 (1 year 9 months) Augusta, Georgia

Progressive Care Unit transitions patients from the ICU to a intermittent level of care. Patient population includes Cardiac, Stroke, CHF, PCI Care pre and post op, trauma, COPD, CIWA patients and many other illness.

Clinical Practice Leader PCU/4E MS-Renal November 2017 - August 2018 (10 months) Augusta, Georgia

Clinical Practice Leader directs education through the use of the Donna Wright Model for healthcare education. Encourages development of staff in degree

advancement and certifications. Critical care certification instructor. Drive quality care through competency based education.

Medical Staffing Options
Registered Nurse
June 2017 - November 2017 (6 months)
Augusta, Georgia

Critical care travel nurse working between PCU and ICU.

Nightingale Nurses
Registered Nurse
August 2016 - June 2017 (11 months)
South Bend, Indiana Area

Travel nurse with critical care experience. Specialties include ER, Neuro IR, Neuro ICU Step down, Tele, MICU, SICU and Neuro ICU.

Lake Michigan College Adjunct Instructor December 2016 - May 2017 (6 months) Benton Harbor, Michigan Area

Clinical instructor Med/Surg 2.

Crouse Hospital
Registered Nurse, Neurosurgical Interventional Radiology
October 2014 - August 2016 (1 year 11 months)
syracuse, new york area

Register Nurse in the Neurosurgical Interventional Radiology Suite. Assisting with IR procedures, blood pressure monitoring, documentation of procedures, assist in pre and post operative care along with more tasks.

St Joseph's Hospital Health Center Registered Nurse Emergency Department December 2013 - October 2014 (11 months) syracuse, new york area

Registered Nurse in the Emergency Department. Assess patients in an acute emergency setting, guide care of patients through triage and assessment, help implement tests and labs that assist the physician in identifying the patient condition or illness. Critical thinking, team approach to healthcare is what guides my excellence. Working within a team to identify steps needed to care effectively for the critically ill as well as the general population within the Syracuse community. Placement assistance and direction for those who are

uninsured or have need for a primary care physicians. Assisting physician with bedside procedures in an emergent and non emergent manner in addition to patient education on disease processes and prevention.

Cardiovascular Group of Syracuse Registered Nurse Cardiology July 2012 - December 2013 (1 year 6 months) fayetteville, new york

Interim Nursing Manager.

Private cardiovascular practice RN, in charge of daily operations of nursing staff, training, scheduling, triage, Coumadin clinic, Pacemaker clinic, stress testing including nuclear stress, stress echo, adenosine/dobutimine stress testing. Primary patient teaching including diet modification, Coumadin teaching, smoking cessation and general health teaching. cardiac event recorders, review of medications and laboratory results, insurance prior authorizations, compensation, and disability, etc. Preparation of patient charts including coordination with other practices and surgery center for procedures like Cardioversion and cardiac catheterizations, EP lab procedures, and pacemaker/internal defibrillator insertion. Implement procedures and policies.

SUNY Upstate Medical University
Registered Nurse Neurosurgical ICU Stepdown
September 2009 - May 2012 (2 years 9 months)
Syracuse, New York Area

Registered nurse on the Neurosurgical Step Down Unit. Silver Award Winners for our Stroke Center.

Charge nurse for a 16 bed ICU Intermediate care unit. Dealing primarily in Neurology and Neurosurgical Patients. Assisted physicians in bedside procedures such as ventriculostomy, lumbar puncture, subdural bolts. Assessed neurologically impaired patients in an acute setting, caring for ventilated patients, stroke patients, post operative pituitary tumors, EEG monitoring, GBS and Myathenia Gravis, along with many other neurological and non neurological conditions.

Member of the unit counsel, driving safety and improvement initiatives to manage the health of our patient population.

Saint Joseph Regional Medical Center Specialty Tech, Stroke Unit and ICU January 2007 - July 2009 (2 years 7 months) South Bend, Indiana Area worked in the ICU as a Specialty Tech, my job included direct patient care, assist RN and Doctors in procedures, Unit secretary duties, ecg strip interpretation, trach care, and a variety of other tasks as directed by the RN.

**Arcadia Services** 

CNA/ HHA

November 2005 - January 2007 (1 year 3 months)

Traveled to area hospitals and staffed. I worked at Lakeland, Borgess Lee Memorial, Paw Paw, and did homecare in Niles and Buchanan.

## Education

Western Governors University

Master of Science (M.S.), Nursing Education · (2014 - 2016)

Baker College Center for Graduate Studies

Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Nursing Science · (2012 - 2014)

Ivy Tech Community College

ASN, Nursing · (2006 - 2009)

Baker College Business and Corporate Services

BA, Business · (2005 - 2007)

Western Michigan University

Bachelor of Business Administration - BBA, Business · (2003 - 2005)